What would happen if Earth actually was
flat? Would we fall off? Would we spin
into the edge? It's even weirder than
you think. Because for a sphere, [music]
gravity pulls in the same direction from
all points on the surface. But for a
disc-shaped Earth, gravity depends on
where you're standing. In the center,
gravity pulls you down, but as you walk
towards the edges, gravity pulls you
down and sideways. And the consequences
of that, well, all the ocean water would
be pulled towards the center, trees
would grow diagonally to fight against
gravity, and it would be near impossible
to reach the outer edges of the Earth
because the sideways gravity would make
it feel like climbing a never-ending
mountain. And on top of that, our
flattened Earth has no internal layers,
and it's the movement of our molten
liquid core that causes our magnetic
field. So, without it, we're just
getting cooked by cosmic radiation. And
depending on our orientation, there
would be only day or only night. And
lunar eclipses look like this. So, if
Earth was flat, we'd be cooking on a
space pan with no escape. To find out
how scientists know what's really inside
the Earth, [music] subscribe.